Holocaust Collection 0008.003.004a
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
- Photo Series II: Europe and Holocaust Photographs
  - Europe and Holocaust/Gravestone of Esther Einstein, Poland, c. 1928, undated; original negative with copy (Box 2)
    Jacob Mosha Einstein standing by the gravestone of his grandmother, c. 1928.
    Einstein, Esther, d. 1928; Gravestones
  - Europe and Holocaust/Musicians, quartet and choral groups, 1930s, undated; two photos w/ negatives (Box 2)
    Photos donated by Mrs. Alex Lifshitz 7/2/1979.
    Shub, Rebecca Rivke; Holocaust; Music
  - Europe and Holocaust/Netherlands, World War II, children's class, children wearing Star of David, includes Ruth Fishman, undated (Box 2)
    Class picture in Holland [note Star of David on clothing]
    Fishman, Ruth Lichtenstern, Homemaker, Volunteer, b.1935, Cologne, Germany; Anti-Semitism; Education; Holocaust
  - Europe and Holocaust/Poland, Market Place, undated; 1 photo with negatives (Box 2)
    Marketplace in Poland, place unknown and undated.
    pre-Nazi Europe
  - Europe and Holocaust/Poland, Wolkowitz in 1920s, 1918-1928; 8 photographs with negatives (Box 2)
    4 -8 scenes of European life- _ Wolkowitz. Poland.— 1. 1928 - Cohen family before depart.for US 2. 1918 - Max Cohen in front of Barber shop- "Friseur" 3. 1925 - Abe Cohen (Kilikowski) 4. 1925 - Charles Cohen 5. 1922 - Shomer Atzoyen-Jewish Boy Scouts. 6. 1925 - Maccabee Soccer team 7. 1928 - Volunteer Fireman's Band 8. 1927 - Wolkowitz Railroad Band (taken at Lida, Poland - on tour)
    Cohen, Abraham; Cohen, Charles; Businesses -- Barber Shop; Holocaust; Music; pre-Nazi Europe; Sports -- Soccer
  - Europe and Holocaust/Russia, soldiers, 1913, photocopy image (Box 2)
    pre-Nazi Europe; Russia
  - Europe and Holocaust/Sephardic Jewry, undated; 1 photocopy image (Box 2)
    Photocopy image of Old Jewish Quarter in Segovia, Spain.
    pre-Nazi Europe; Sephardic Jewry; Synagogues
  - Europe and Holocaust/Shul in Poland, 1890s; photograph w/ negative and photocopy image (Box 2)
    pre-Nazi Europe; Religious Life; Synagogues
  - Europe and Holocaust/Shul at Volpa, Russia, undated; 1 photo image of printed lithograph (Box 2)
    Jewish life in Europe; pre-Nazi Germany; Synagogues
  - Europe and Holocaust/Spiro/Shapiro family, Czechoslovakia, 1930s-1940s, Two photos with original negatives (Box 2)
    Hasidic rabbis with father, Yechiel Shapiro
    Shapiro family
    Shapiro, Czeckoslovakia; Eastern European Jews; Jewish life in Europe; pre-Nazi Germany; Rabbinate
- Holocaust Artifacts, 1930s-1940s; 3 medals
  Artifacts; Holocaust; Nazis/ Nazi Germany
  - German Security of State medal, 1940s; 1 object -- bronze medal w/ ribbon; Bronze medal with orange and white ribbon. Medal depicts Nazi symbol on front and text on back "Fur Arbeit Zum Schutze Deutsch-lands". (Box Artifacts)
    Artifacts; Holocaust; Nazis/ Nazi Germany; World War II
  - German Sports medal, 1930s; 1 object -- bronze medal w/ ribbon; Small broze medal with red and black ribbon. Nazi icon and sports figures on front, and text on back - "Ein volk, Ein Reich, Ein Fuhrer" 1 October 1938" (One country, one people, one leader) (Box Artifacts)
    Holocaust; Nazis/ Nazi Germany; Sports; World War II
  - German Insignia patch worn by railroad worker, 1940s; 1 object -- cloth patch; Cloth insignia patch with military bars (corporal stripes) and Nazi icon .. wing emerging from railroad wheel. Black cloth with red embroidered boarder and gold relief. (Box Artifacts)
    Holocaust; Nazis/ Nazi Germany; World War II